const question = document.querySelector('#question');
const choices = Array.from(document.querySelectorAll('.choice-text'));
const progressText = document.querySelector('#progressText');
const scoreText = document.querySelector('#score');
const progressBarFull = document.querySelector('#progressBarFull');

let currentQuestion = {};
let acceptingAnswers = true;
let score = 0;
let questionCounter = 0;
let availableQuestions = [];

let questions = [
	{
		question: 'Who was the best football player of Europe in 1998?',
		choice1: 'Marcel Desailly from Milan and Chelsea',
		choice2: 'Lilian Thuram from Parma',
		choice3: 'Zinedine Zidane from Juventus',
		choice4: 'Michael Owen from Liverpool',
		answer: 3,
	},
	{
		question: 'When was the first Premier League played?',
		choice1: '1891-92',
		choice2: '1952-53',
		choice3: '1985-86',
		choice4: '1992-93',
		answer: 4,
	},
	{
		question:
			'In 1990, this team failed to score even one goal in the World Cup final',
		choice1: 'Argentina',
		choice2: 'Brazil',
		choice3: 'Paris Saint-Germain',
		choice4: 'Portugal',
		answer: 1,
	},
	{
		question: 'Whcih played scores the fastest hat-trick in Premier League',
		choice1: 'Eric Cantona',
		choice2: 'Sadio Mane',
		choice3: 'Brian Deane',
		choice4: 'Rod Wallace',
		answer: 2,
	},
	{
		question:
			'Which Barcalona player was jailed after it was found that his password was fake?',
		choice1: 'Jordi Alba',
		choice2: 'Martin Braithwaite',
		choice3: 'Ronald Araujo',
		choice4: 'Ronaldinho',
		answer: 4,
	},
	{
		question: 'Who was the first Premier League manager who was fired?',
		choice1: 'Ian Porterfield',
		choice2: 'George Graham',
		choice3: 'Stewart Houston',
		choice4: 'Bruce Rioch',
		answer: 1,
	},
	{
		question: 'When was the original FA Cup Trophy Stolen? ',
		choice1: '1900',
		choice2: '1885',
		choice3: '1895',
		choice4: '1845',
		answer: 3,
	},
	{
		question:
			'After how many games did Cristiano Ronaldo score his first Champions League goal?',
		choice1: '27',
		choice2: '17',
		choice3: '5',
		choice4: '36',
		answer: 1,
	},
	{
		question:
			'In which club did Nicky Byrne play before finding his calling in Music?',
		choice1: 'Everton',
		choice2: 'Leeds United',
		choice3: 'Tottenham',
		choice4: 'Manchester City',
		answer: 2,
	},
	{
		question: 'Liverpool was founded in which year?',
		choice1: '1890',
		choice2: '1950',
		choice3: '1892',
		choice4: '1991',
		answer: 3,
	},
];

const SCORE_POINTS = 100;
const MAX_QUESTIONS = 10;

startGame = () => {
	questionCounter = 0;
	score = 0;
	availableQuestions = [...questions];
	getNewQuestion();
};

getNewQuestion = () => {
	if (availableQuestions.length === 0 || questionCounter > MAX_QUESTIONS) {
		localStorage.setItem('mostRecentScore', score);

		return window.location.assign('/football/end');
	}

	questionCounter++;
	progressText.innerText = `Question ${questionCounter} of ${MAX_QUESTIONS}`;
	progressBarFull.style.width = `${(questionCounter / MAX_QUESTIONS) * 100}%`;

	const questionsIndex = Math.floor(
		Math.random() * availableQuestions.length
	);
	currentQuestion = availableQuestions[questionsIndex];
	question.innerText = currentQuestion.question;

	choices.forEach((choice) => {
		const number = choice.dataset['number'];
		choice.innerText = currentQuestion['choice' + number];
	});

	availableQuestions.splice(questionsIndex, 1);

	acceptingAnswers = true;
};

choices.forEach((choice) => {
	choice.addEventListener('click', (e) => {
		if (!acceptingAnswers) return;

		acceptingAnswers = false;
		const selectedChoice = e.target;
		const selectedAnswer = selectedChoice.dataset['number'];

		let classToApply =
			selectedAnswer == currentQuestion.answer ? 'correct' : 'incorrect';

		if (classToApply === 'correct') {
			incrementScore(SCORE_POINTS);
		}

		if (classToApply === 'incorrect') {
			decrementScore(SCORE_POINTS);
		}

		selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.add(classToApply);

		setTimeout(() => {
			selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.remove(classToApply);
			getNewQuestion();
		}, 1000);
	});
});

incrementScore = (num) => {
	score += num;
	scoreText.innerText = score;
};

// function to deduct 100 points for wrong answer
decrementScore = (num) => {
	score -= num;
	scoreText.innerText = score;
};

startGame();
